# Mohamad Naji

# **Software Developer**

mohamadd.najii@gmail.com

+1 (514) 606-2270

Montréal-Nord, Canada

linkedin.com/in/mohamad-na ii-b84310174

Software developer with 5 years of experience, trained at the Lebanese University, and having worked at Cedar IT Services and Capital Banking Solutions. Currently a Full-Stack Developer at MyMonty, specializing in backend services and APIs. Skilled in Java, Spring Boot, Python, and SQL, with a strong passion for innovation and collaboration.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# MyMonty (Monty Mobile) - Senior Full Stack Developer

Nov 2022 - current Remotely

- Created 30+ RESTful APIs with Java Spring Boot, incorporating OpenAPI and Swagger for precise API specifications.
- Crafted dynamic microservices with Java Spring Boot, revolutionizing application architecture.
- Pioneered Java Spring Data architectures with SQL Server and MySQL, embedding Redis caching for lightning-fast performance.
- Leveraged Java 17 and 21 to implement innovative features, boosting application performance by 30%.
- Developed java code following common security practices and development design patterns.
- Developed innovative unit tests with JUnit and Mockito, enhancing core functionality while decreasing bug incidence.
- Used RabbitMQ for efficient request organization and Firebase for Android push notifications.
- Collaborated in Agile sprints using Jira for project management, Git for version control, and Docker for containerization.
- Implemented scalable integration services for card and exchange management with multiple provider.

# Capital Banking Solutions - Software Developer

Oct 2021 - Oct 2022 Lebanon

- Developed innovative APIs and features for enterprise applications leveraging Java frameworks like Oracle ADF and Spring Boot.
- Designed and implemented database using Oracle database and PL/SQL.
- Streamlined development processes by conducting detailed code reviews, reducing bug rates by 25%.

# Cedar IT Services - Software Engineer

Nov 2019 - Aug 2021 Lebanon

- Contributed to projects in the banking industry, collaborating with Banque du Liban and Al Rajhi Bank, and other banks.
- Engineered innovative features with Java JSF and Spring Boot.
- Optimizing data management using Java Spring Data and Oracle databases.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of 10+ new features, meeting 100% of client specifications.
- Maintained and enhanced existing functions and addressing client needs on multiple environement.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Real Estate Price Prediction in Lebanon using machine learning - MS senior project

- Implemented web scraping tool using python Beautiful Soup and Selenium for real estate data collection.
- Built a machine learning model with Optuna for hyperparameter tuning.
- Developed a responsive user interface using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, with a FastAPI backend for efficient data processing and API integration.

# Base Station Configuration - BS Senior prejoct

- Developed an Antenna Recommendation System using PHP and the Laravel framework.
- Optimized antenna filtration processes with dynamic programming, reducing computation time by 99.57%.
- Redesigned the web interface with JQuery and Bootstrap, improving navigation and user satisfaction.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Lebanese University - Master's degree, GIS and data science

2022 - 2024 Beirut

#### Relevant courses

Python; Deep learning; Big data; NLP; Remote sensing; Geodatabase; Spatial analysis

## Lebanese University - Bachelor's degree, computer science

2016 - 2019 Beirut

#### Relevant courses

Java; PHP; Design pattern; Data structure; Database; Operating system; Parallel programming; System administration

#### **SKILLS**

## **Programming languages**

Java; Python; Javascript; PHP; SQL

#### **Frameworks**

Spring boot; JSF - java server faces; Oracle ADF; JQuery; Laravel(beginner); Angular(beginner)

#### **Tools**

Maven; Liquibase; Rabbitmq; Firebase; Camel; Git; Jira; SVN; Redis; Lombok; Logging; MapStruct; Design pattern; SQL server; MySql; Oracle PISql; Intellij; JBoss; Eclipse; JUnit; Swagger; OpenApi; Postman; Docker; Prometheus; Fluentd; Grafana; Spacy; NLTK; ArcGis pro

### Languages

English; French; Arabic

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Esri Lebanon: Spatial Analysis with ArcGIS
- Esri Lebanon: Python for geospatial Al
- Esri Lebanon: Geodatabase Concepts: Design and Modeling
- Esri Lebanon: Creating and Sharing GIS content using Web GIS
- Build modern web applications with Angular